[{"id":"1885","question":"<p><span style=\"color:#000000\">Approximately what is the overall percentage of marks obtained by T in all subjects?&nbsp;<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"79     ","option2":"82","option3":"86","option4":"72","option5":"76","correct_option":"72","qa_date":"2015-07-23 15:43:40","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol>\r\n\t<li>Marks obtained by T in<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">&nbsp;H = 67&times; <a name=\"OLE_LINK2\"><\/a><a name=\"OLE_LINK1\">&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/a>= 68&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;\/sub&gt;=51<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">G = 74&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;\/sub&gt;= 75&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;= 45<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">M = 45<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">S = 84 &times;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;\/sub&gt;=42<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">E = 85 &times;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=34<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">H = 80 &times;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt; =32<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">Total mark obtained<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">= 51 + 45 + 45 + 42 + 34 + 32= 249 = 250 (approximately)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">Total marks= 75 + 60 + 80 + 50 + 40 + 40 =345<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">So, Required percentage = &lt;sup&gt;250&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;345&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100 = 72%<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1920","question":"<p>The no of E type vehicles exported in 2007 is equal to the number of which type of vehicles exported in 2008?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"C only ","option2":"D only ","option3":"A only","option4":"Both C and B","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"None of these","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:26:40","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The correct answer is A and C.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1913","question":"<p>What was the approximate percentage increases in the number of students of Engineering<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>From the year 2001 to 2002?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"17","option2":"15","option3":"25","option4":"23","option5":"20","correct_option":"20","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:32:41","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Difference = 7600-6300=1300<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required percentage increase = &lt;sup&gt;1300&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6300&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 20.63 = 20&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1996","question":"<p>When cutting and pasting. The item cut is temporarily stored in&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"ROM","option2":"Hard drive ","option3":"Diskette  ","option4":"Dashboard ","option5":"Clipboard ","correct_option":"Clipboard ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:51:56","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1971","question":"<p>The approach of &lsquo;micro-credit&rsquo; or &lsquo;Banking with the poor&rsquo; is comparatively a new concept in the field of rural credit. This approach has been tried very successfully in which of the following countries?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Bangladesh","option2":"India","option3":"China","option4":"Japan ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Bangladesh","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:35:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1917","question":"<p>Total exports in 2007 and 2008 together was equal in case of which of the following pairs of types?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A and E","option2":"B and C","option3":"A and D","option4":"B and D","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"A and E","qa_date":"2015-09-27 09:55:04","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Total exports in 2007 and 2008 together<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>A: 20 + 25 = 45<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>E: 25 + 20 = 45<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1957","question":"<p>What is backup?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Adding more components to your networks  ","option2":"Accessing data on tape ","option3":"Filtering old data from the new data","option4":"Protecting data by copying it from the original source to a different destination ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Protecting data by copying it from the original source to a different destination ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 00:27:46","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1918","question":"<p>The percentage change (increase or decrease) in the number of vehicles exported from 2007 to 2008 is minimum in the case of which of the following types of vehicle?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"D","qa_date":"2015-09-27 09:56:38","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>% of change from 2007 to 2008<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>D: <sup>25-20<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>20<\/sub>&times;100=25%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1888","question":"<p>What are the total marks obtained by L in History, Geography and Mathematics?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"221.8","option2":"253","option3":"180.2","option4":"184","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"180.2","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:01:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Marks&nbsp;obtained by L in<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>History = 88&times;= &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;\/sub&gt;=66<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Geography = 89&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;Maths = 76&times;= &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;\/sub&gt;=60.8<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;Total = 66+53.4+60.8=180.2<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1954","question":"<p>In which of the following cities India&rsquo;s first monorail service has been launched, recently?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Bangalore   ","option2":"Kolkata ","option3":"Chennai  ","option4":"Mumbai","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Mumbai","qa_date":"2015-07-25 00:21:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1942","question":"<p><span style=\"color:black; font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9pt\">A box contains 2 white balls, 3 black balls and 4 red balls. In how many ways can 3 balls be drawn from the box, if at least one black ball is to be included in the draw?<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"32","option2":"48 ","option3":"64","option4":"96","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"64","qa_date":"2015-07-23 22:08:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>We may have(1 black and 2 non-black) or (2 black and 1 non-black) or (3 black).<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><span style=\"line-height:1.6\">Required number of ways = (<\/span><sup>3<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>) + (<sup>3<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>)&nbsp;+&nbsp;<sup>3<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub><br \/>\r\n<span style=\"line-height:1.6\">= (45 + 18 + 1)<\/span>= (3 x &lt;sup&gt;6 x 5&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;) + (&lt;sup&gt;3 x 2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;x6) + 1<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 64<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1937","question":"<p>3&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 13&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 38&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 87&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 166&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 289&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"38 ","option2":"13","option3":"87","option4":"166","option5":"4","correct_option":"166","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:20:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The given number series is based on the following pattern.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>4 &ndash; 3 = 1<sup>2 <\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;13 &ndash; 4 = 9 = 3<sup>2<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>38 &ndash; 13 = 25 = 5<sup>2<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>87 &ndash; 38 = 49 = 7<sup>2<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>168 &ndash; 87 = 81 = 9<sup>2<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>289 &ndash; 168 = 121 = 11<sup>2<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Obviously, 166 is the wrong number.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1908","question":"<p>During which of the following pairs of years, the strength of schools equal?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1994 and 1995","option2":"1995 and 1997","option3":"1996 and 1998 ","option4":"1995 and 1998","option5":"1993 and 1995","correct_option":"1993 and 1995","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:42:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In 1993 the strenght of school =&nbsp;1500+300-250=1550<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>In 1995&nbsp;the strenght of school =&nbsp;1450+500-400=1550<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1893","question":"<p>What is the percent profit earned in 2001-2002?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"200","option2":"125","option3":"100","option4":"125","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"100","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:03:18","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Income in 2001-2002 = Rs.250crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Expenditure in 2001-2002 = Rs. 125crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, percent profit = = &lt;sup&gt;250-125&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;125&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=100<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1997","question":"<p>For effective marketing the salesmen should have which of these qualities?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Creativity","option2":"Team spirit","option3":"Motivation","option4":"Effective communication skills","option5":"All of these","correct_option":"All of these","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:53:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1991","question":"<p>When you are working on documents on PC, where is the document temporarily stored?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"RAM ","option2":"ROM ","option3":"The CPU   ","option4":"Flash memory   ","option5":"The CD-ROM ","correct_option":"RAM ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:37:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1901","question":"<p>For course D what is the respective ratio of boys and girls?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"3:4","option2":"4:5","option3":"3:5","option4":"5:6","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"3:4","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:46:30","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required ratio = 180:240=3:4<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1951","question":"<p>In the field of computers, which of the following converter inverts into output?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Mouse","option2":"Trackball","option3":"Keyboard    ","option4":"Bar Code Reader   ","option5":"Light pen ","correct_option":"Bar Code Reader   ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 18:24:02","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1952","question":"<p>What is meant by &ldquo;Underwriting&rdquo; the&nbsp; term frequency used in financial sector?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Under valuation of the assets   ","option2":"The act of taking on a risk for a fee    ","option3":"Giving a Guarantee that a loan will not become a bad loan   ","option4":"The act of permission to float an IPO  ","option5":"None of these  ","correct_option":"Under valuation of the assets   ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 23:56:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1925","question":"<p>Total how many students speak in English?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"304","option2":"79","option3":"225","option4":"117","option5":"None of these  ","correct_option":"304","qa_date":"2015-07-23 04:48:46","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of students who speak English<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 108 + 55 + 117 + 24 + = 304<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1887","question":"<p>What are the average marks obtained by all the students in Geography?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"51.34","option2":"85.57","option3":"52.36","option4":"76.27","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"51.34","qa_date":"2015-07-21 22:58:49","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol>\r\n\t<li>Marks obtained in Geography by<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>P = 82&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=49.2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Q = 78&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=46.8<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>R = 94&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=56.4<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>T = 74&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=44.4<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>M = 86&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=51.6<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>L = 89&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=53.4<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required average&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= &lt;sup&gt;49.2+46.8+56.4+44.4+51.6+53.4&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>c=51.34<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1946","question":"<p>Which of the following pair wins 2015 Australian Open Mixed Double Title?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Leander Paes, Martina Navratilova        ","option2":"Leander Paes, Monica Seles","option3":"Leander Paes, Martina Hingis       ","option4":"Roser  Federer, Martina Hingis       ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Leander Paes, Martina Hingis       ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 22:56:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1975","question":"<p>Computers that are portable and convenient for users who travel are known as&mdash;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Super computers    ","option2":"Laptops ","option3":"mini computers   ","option4":"file servers   ","option5":"None of these   ","correct_option":"Laptops ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:54:07","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1993","question":"<p>In which of the following countries world&rsquo;s highest tunnel for high-speed train has been opened recently?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"China","option2":"Russia ","option3":"Japan","option4":" Singapore","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"China","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:42:18","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1981","question":"<p>When we run a program in HTML coding,- is used as backend and &ndash;works as fronted.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Notepad \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Internet \u00e2\u20ac\u201cEx-plorer ","option2":"Notepad \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Msn- messenger ","option3":"MS-word \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Internet Ex- plorer ","option4":"Both (1) and (2) ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Notepad \u00e2\u20ac\u201c Internet \u00e2\u20ac\u201cEx-plorer ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 17:20:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1886","question":"<p>What is the overall percentage of marks&nbsp;obtained by M in all the subjects (rounded off two digits after decimal)?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"82.74","option2":"84.76","option3":"76.84","option4":"74.87","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"84.76","qa_date":"2015-07-21 22:56:26","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Marked obtained by M&nbsp; in<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>H = 74 &times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;\/sub&gt;= 76 &times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;\/sub&gt;=57<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>G = 86 &times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;= 90&times;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=54<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>M = 64 &times;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=60&times;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=48<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>S= 40<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>E = 78&times;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;= 80&times;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=32<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>H = 72&times;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;= 70&times;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;=28<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Total marked obtained = 57 + 54 + 48 +40 + 32 + 28 = 259&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Total marks = 345 Required percentage = &lt;sup&gt;259&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;345&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100= 84.46<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1895","question":"<p>What is the average income (in crore Rs) for the given years?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"265","option2":"1550","option3":"160","option4":"250","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"None of these","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:04:55","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required average income<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Rs. = &lt;sup&gt;(150+200+325+350+250)&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. = &lt;sup&gt;1275&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. 255crores&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"2001","question":"<p>What does the letter &lsquo;M&rsquo; depict in the term SME as used in the financial world?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Maximum ","option2":"Medium  ","option3":"Mercantile   ","option4":"Mutual ","option5":"Ministry ","correct_option":"Medium  ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:18:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1959","question":"<p>Who is the present Foreign Secretary of India in Modi&rsquo;s Government?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Sujata Singh       ","option2":"Ajit Doval       ","option3":"S Jaishankar        ","option4":"Ranjan Mathai","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"S Jaishankar        ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 03:39:12","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1926","question":"<p>Number of girls speaking only Hindi what percent of the total number of students speaking only Hindi?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"38.2     ","option2":"71.8     ","option3":"31.2     ","option4":"78","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"None of these ","qa_date":"2015-07-23 04:48:46","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required percentage&nbsp;= &lt;sup&gt;78&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;96&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100 = 81.25<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1911","question":"<p>In which faculty there was decrease in the number of students from 2001 to 2002?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"None","option2":"Arts","option3":"Agriculture","option4":"Pharmacy ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Agriculture","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:30:52","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The number of students decrease from 2450 to 2000 in Agriculture&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1889","question":"<p>What are the average percentages&nbsp;&nbsp; of marked obtained by all the students in Mathematics?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"81.92","option2":"81.29","option3":"65.03","option4":"76.23","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"81.29","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:02:12","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required average<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= &lt;sup&gt;95+85+89+74+64+76+86&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;= &lt;sup&gt;569&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;\/sub&gt;=81.285 = 81.29<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1933","question":"<p><strong>I.<\/strong> 9x<sup>2 <\/sup>&ndash; 18x + 5 = 0&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>II<\/strong>. 2y<sup>2 <\/sup>&ndash; 9y + 10 = 0<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"4","qa_date":"2015-07-23 23:37:42","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>9x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 18x + 5 = 0&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>9x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 3x -&nbsp;15x + 5 = 0&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>3x(3x-1)-5(3x-1)= 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = 5\/3 ; 1\/3<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 9y + 10 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 4y - 5y + 10 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2y(y -2) -5(y - 2) = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>y = 5\/2; 2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1989","question":"<p>Recently, an RBI panel has recommended that the Government&nbsp;should reduce its holding in public sector banks to below 50 per cent. This panel was headed by __?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Urjit Patel      ","option2":"PJ Nayak     ","option3":"Chanda  Kocchar      ","option4":"Aruna Upadyaya","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"PJ Nayak     ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 13:01:12","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1978","question":"<p>Eddie Redmayne wins the Best Actor award for which movie in the Oscar 2015<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Bird Man   ","option2":"Still Alice   ","option3":"The Theory of Everything   ","option4":"Ida  ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"The Theory of Everything   ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 17:15:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1969","question":"<p>What is the term for unsolicited e-mail?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Newsgroup","option2":"Usenet ","option3":"backbone   ","option4":"flaming  ","option5":"spam ","correct_option":"spam ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:31:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1921","question":"<p>The average of B and c type vehicles in 2008 was equal to the exports of which type in 2007?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A only  ","option2":"C only","option3":"Both A and C","option4":"Both C and E ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"C only","qa_date":"2015-09-27 10:02:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Average of B and C types of vehicles in 2008<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= <sup>30+25<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>=27.5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1988","question":"<p>The Traditional Marketing style involves<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Telemarketing","option2":"Digital Marketing","option3":"Indirect Marketing","option4":"Direct Marketing","option5":"All of these","correct_option":"Direct Marketing","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:17:25","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"2008","question":"<p>&lsquo;WWW&rsquo; stands for-<\/p>\r\n","option1":"World Word Web ","option2":"World Wide Web  ","option3":"World White Web","option4":"World Work Web ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"World Wide Web  ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 21:03:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1979","question":"<p>The rate of interest charged by RBI for lending money to various commercial banks by rediscounting of the bills in India is called&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Exchange rate   ","option2":"Statutory Liquidity Ratio   ","option3":"Cash Reserve Ratio  ","option4":"Bank Rate  ","option5":"Interest Rate  ","correct_option":"Interest Rate  ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 11:47:26","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1903","question":"<p>For course E, the number of girls is how much percent more than the boys for course E?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"250","option2":"350","option3":"150","option4":"80","option5":"None of these    ","correct_option":"250","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:47:49","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required percentage = = &lt;sup&gt;112-32&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;32&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= &lt;sup&gt;80&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;32&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100 = 250<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1919","question":"<p>The exports of D type vehicle in 2007 was what percentage of exports of E type vehicles in 2008?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"150","option2":"175","option3":"75","option4":"125 ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"175","qa_date":"2015-09-27 09:57:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required % = <sup>35<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>20<\/sub>&times;100= 175%<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1909","question":"<p>The number of students In 1996 is approximately what percent of the number of students in 1994?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"85","option2":"117","option3":"95","option4":"103","option5":"108","correct_option":"117","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:35:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>From solution to Q. No. 204 we have the number of students in 1996 = 1700 and that in 1994 = 1450<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required %=&lt;sup&gt;1700&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1450&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100 = 117 %(approx)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1945","question":"<p>What is the probability of getting a sum 9 from two throws of a dice?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>6<\/sub>           ","option2":"<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>8<\/sub>           ","option3":"<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>9<\/sub>           ","option4":"<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>12<\/sub>    ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>9<\/sub>           ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 01:42:40","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">Solution : P(E) = &lt;sup&gt;<\/span><span style=\"font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9.0pt\">n(E)<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;<\/span><span style=\"font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9.0pt\">n(S)<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&lt;\/sub&gt;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <\/span><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = &lt;sup&gt;<\/span><span style=\"font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9.0pt\">4<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3<\/span><span style=\"font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9.0pt\">6<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&lt;\/sub&gt;&nbsp;&nbsp; <\/span><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;= &lt;sup&gt;<\/span><span style=\"font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9.0pt\">1<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;<\/span><span style=\"font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9.0pt\">9<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&lt;\/sub&gt;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1902","question":"<p>For which pair of courses, is that&nbsp;number of boys the same?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"E and F","option2":"A and D","option3":"C and F ","option4":"B and D","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"C and F ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:47:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of boys in each of courses C and F = 44<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1900","question":"<p>How many girls are there in course C?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"44","option2":"16","option3":"40","option4":"160","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"16","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:45:38","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of girls in course C = 16<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1972","question":"<p>A prospect means<\/p>\r\n","option1":"any customer who walks into the bank","option2":"an employee of the bank","option3":"a customer who is likely to be interested in bank\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s product or service","option4":"a depositor of the bank","option5":"a borrower of the bank","correct_option":"a customer who is likely to be interested in bank\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s product or service","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:48:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1940","question":"<p>The radii of two spheres are in the ratio: 1:3 find the ratio of their volumes.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1:9     ","option2":"1:64     ","option3":"1:27      ","option4":"1:125     ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"1:27      ","qa_date":"2015-07-23 23:50:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>r<sub>1&nbsp;<\/sub>: r<sub>2&nbsp;<\/sub>= 1:3<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Ratio of their volumes = (1\/3)<sup>3<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;= 1\/27<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;= 1:27<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1987","question":"<p>X. 21 protocol consists of&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Physical and frame levels  ","option2":"Frame and Packet levels  ","option3":"Physical, frame and packet levels  ","option4":"Only physical level  ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Only physical level  ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 12:45:34","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1935","question":"<p>7&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 6&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 9&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 20&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 52.5&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 160.5&nbsp; &nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"6 ","option2":"4","option3":"20","option4":"9","option5":"52.5","correct_option":"6 ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:58:38","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>7&times;0.5+0.5 = 4<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>4&times;1+1=<strong> 5<\/strong>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>5<\/strong>&times;1.5+1.5 = 9<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>9&times;2+2&nbsp;= 20<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>20&times;2.5+2.5 = 52.5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>6 is the wrong number.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1927","question":"<p>What is the respective ratio between the number of boys and girls speaking both the languages?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"23:25     ","option2":"12:25    ","option3":"12:13     ","option4":"25:13   ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"12:13     ","qa_date":"2015-07-23 04:48:46","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required ratio &nbsp;= 108:117&nbsp;= 12:13<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"2006","question":"<p>Marketing plan helps in&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"better lead generation","option2":"better systems","option3":"better results","option4":"improved balance sheet","option5":"better customer service","correct_option":"better results","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:57:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1970","question":"<p>The planning Commissions of India is renamed as &ndash;&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"NITI Darshan       ","option2":"NITI Aayog        ","option3":"NITI  Mandal       ","option4":"not changed    ","option5":"None of the above","correct_option":"NITI Aayog        ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:33:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1955","question":"<p>What is it called when computer connects to other computers and sends information?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"LAN ","option2":"Remote Desktop    ","option3":"Boot  ","option4":"Network ","option5":"Internet protocol   ","correct_option":"Remote Desktop    ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 00:23:14","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1905","question":"<p>What was the increase\/decrease in strength of the school from 1994 to 1995?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Increase by 100","option2":"Decrease by 100","option3":"Increase by 200 ","option4":"Decrease by 200","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Increase by 100","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:36:16","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of student who left in the beginning of 1995 = 400<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Number of students who joined in the beginning of 1995 = 500<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, There was net increase of 100(=500-400) students in the strength of the school from 1994 to 1995.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1894","question":"<p>What is the different in the percent profit in1999-2000 and 2000-2001?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"25","option2":"20","option3":"5","option4":"10","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"10","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:04:12","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Percent profit in 1999-2000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:18.0pt\">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = &lt;sup&gt;325-250&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;250&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=30<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Percent profit in 2000-2001= &lt;sup&gt;350-250&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;250&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=40<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, Required difference = 10<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1992","question":"<p>A true marketing requires<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Command and other mindset","option2":"Control Mindset","option3":"Passive mindset","option4":"Active mindset","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Active mindset","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:39:59","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1986","question":"<p>A Call means<\/p>\r\n","option1":"calling on friends","option2":"calling on bank employees","option3":"calling on prospective customers","option4":"to make telephone calls","option5":"calling on relatives","correct_option":"calling on prospective customers","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:09:04","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1956","question":"<p>The government of India has launched a new initiative called MeghRaj. What is this MeghRaj?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"It is a Monsoon prediction system      ","option2":"It\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s a project related to Cloud Computing   ","option3":"It\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s a  service under Department of Posts    ","option4":"It\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s a new scheme for India\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s Rain fed areas","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"It\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s a project related to Cloud Computing   ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 00:25:36","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1943","question":"<p><span style=\"color:black; font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9pt\">In how many ways a committee, consisting of 5 men and 6 women can be formed from 8 men and 10 women?<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"266","option2":"5040","option3":"11760","option4":"86400  ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"11760","qa_date":"2015-07-23 22:24:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required number of ways = (<sup>8<\/sup>C<sub>5<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>10<\/sup>C<sub>6<\/sub>)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; =&nbsp;(<sup>8<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>10<\/sup>C<sub>4<\/sub>)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; =&nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;8 x 7 x 6&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3 x 2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt; x (&lt;sup&gt;10 x 9 x 8 x 7&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4 x 3 x 2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; =&nbsp;11760.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1953","question":"<p>What is Rupee depreciation?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rupee depreciation means that rupee has become less valuable with respect to dollar","option2":"Rupee depreciation means dollar has become less valuable than rupee","option3":"Rupee Depreciation means a situation when value of rupee is same as euro ","option4":"Rupee depreciation happens when the combined value of dollar and euro is more than rupee","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Rupee depreciation means that rupee has become less valuable with respect to dollar","qa_date":"2015-07-25 00:17:13","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"2002","question":"<p>Market Research is needed for<\/p>\r\n","option1":"checking the market area","option2":"checking the right product to be sold","option3":"making proper marketing decisions","option4":"deciding right time to sell","option5":"All of these","correct_option":"All of these","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:20:51","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1984","question":"<p>Which among the following countries is the biggest oil producer in Africa?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Algeria ","option2":"Angola","option3":"Nigeria","option4":"Sudan ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Nigeria","qa_date":"2015-07-25 17:28:42","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1976","question":"<p>A lead means?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"a political leader","option2":"a prospect who is more likely to avail of the Bank\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s product","option3":"a religious leader","option4":"a bank chairman","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"a prospect who is more likely to avail of the Bank\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s product","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:55:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1941","question":"<p><span style=\"color:black; font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9pt\">From a group of 7 men and 6 women, five persons are to be selected to form a committee so that at least 3 men are there on the committee. In how many ways can it be done?<\/span><span style=\"font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">&nbsp;<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"564","option2":"645","option3":"735","option4":"756","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"756","qa_date":"2015-07-23 22:20:54","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>We may have (3 men and 2 women) or (4 men and 1 woman) or (5 men only).<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required number of ways =&nbsp;(<sup>7<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>) +&nbsp;(<sup>7<\/sup>C<sub>4<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>) +&nbsp;<sup>7<\/sup>C<sub>5<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; =&nbsp;(&lt;sup&gt;7 x 6 x 5&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3 x 2 x 1&lt;\/sub&gt; x &lt;sup&gt;6 x 5&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2 x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;) + (<sup>7<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>) + <sup>7<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sub>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/sub>=&nbsp;525 + (&lt;sup&gt;7 x 6 x 5&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3 x 2 x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;&nbsp;x 6) + (&lt;sup&gt;7&nbsp;x 6&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2 x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; = (525 + 210 + 21)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; = 756.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1994","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences is true?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Marketing is not required in a Buyers\u00e2\u20ac\u2122 Market","option2":"Marketing is not required in a Sellers\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s market","option3":"Marketing is not required due to competition","option4":"Marketing is not required due to liberalization","option5":"Marketing is not required due to globalisation","correct_option":"Marketing is not required in a Sellers\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s market","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:46:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1929","question":"<p><strong>I<\/strong>. 2x<sup>2 <\/sup>-7x + 6 = 0&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;II<\/strong>. 4y<sup>2 <\/sup>= 9&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"5","qa_date":"2015-07-23 22:37:55","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>2x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>-7x + 6 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>- 4x - 3x +6 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2x(x-2) - 3(x-2) = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = 2; x = 3\/2.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>4y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>= 9&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>y = +3\/2, -3\/2<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1983","question":"<p>For separating channels in FDM, it is necessary to use&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"time slots ","option2":"Bandpass filters   ","option3":"Differentiation ","option4":"All of these ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Bandpass filters   ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 17:25:30","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1906","question":"<p>For which of the following years, the percentage rise\/fall in number of students left from the previous years is the highest?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1994 ","option2":"1995 ","option3":"1996","option4":"1997","option5":"1998","correct_option":"1997","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:37:50","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Percentage rise\/fall in number of students left from the previous years in<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1994= (= &lt;sup&gt;350-250&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;250&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(= &lt;sup&gt;100&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;250&lt;\/sub&gt;)&times;100 = 40%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1995 = &lt;sup&gt;400-350&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;350&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100 =(&lt;sup&gt;50&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;350&lt;\/sub&gt;)&times;100=14%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1996 = (&lt;sup&gt;400-300&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;400&lt;\/sub&gt;)&times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;= (&lt;sup&gt;100&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;400&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100 = 25%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1997 = (&lt;sup&gt;500-300&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;300&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= (&lt;sup&gt;200&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;300&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100 = 66.7<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1998 = (&lt;sup&gt;500-500&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;500&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= (&lt;sup&gt;0&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;500&lt;\/sub&gt;) &times;100= 0%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required percentage is the highest is 1997.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"2004","question":"<p>The &ldquo;National Working Plan Code&rdquo; is a tool for management of ___?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"May 1          ","option2":"May 3       ","option3":"May 5       ","option4":"May 6      ","option5":"May 10                   ","correct_option":"May 3       ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:29:00","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1923","question":"<p>Total how many boys speak Hindi?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"18","option2":"26","option3":"108  ","option4":"126","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"126","qa_date":"2015-07-23 04:48:46","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of boys who speak Hindi<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 18 + 108 = 126<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1977","question":"<p>Indian-born Punith Ranjen appointed as CEO of-<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Deloitte","option2":"Twitter ","option3":"LinkedIn ","option4":"Accenture ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Deloitte","qa_date":"2015-07-25 17:13:28","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1985","question":"<p>Which one of the following was the reason owing to which Government wants Reserve Bank of India to tighten prudential norms for NBFCs?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"To reduce liquidity in the market ","option2":"II is as per Basel II requirement ","option3":"II is as per banks for international settlement (BIS) directives ","option4":"It is to protect NBFCs from any impact of possible economic slowdown ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"It is to protect NBFCs from any impact of possible economic slowdown ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:04:17","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1990","question":"<p>Expand the term ALM as used in Banking\/Financial Sector?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Asset Liability Mismatch  ","option2":"Asset Liability Maturity ","option3":"Asset Liability Management ","option4":"Asset Liability Manpower   ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Asset Liability Management ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:35:12","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1980","question":"<p>Innovation means<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Compensation","option2":"inspiration","option3":"additional perquisites","option4":"implementing new ideas or new methods","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"implementing new ideas or new methods","qa_date":"2015-07-25 17:19:12","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1995","question":"<p>What are teaser loan rates charged by banks?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Fixed rate of interest charged by banks ","option2":"Floating rate of interest charged by banks  ","option3":"Rate of interest in the initial period is less and goes up subsequently ","option4":"Rate of the interest in the initial period is more is goes down subsequently ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Rate of interest in the initial period is less and goes up subsequently ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:48:30","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"2007","question":"<p>&lsquo;Smart Money&rsquo; is a term used for&mdash;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Internet Banking       ","option2":"Credit Card       ","option3":"Cash with Bank    ","option4":"Cash with Public","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Credit Card       ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:59:50","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1915","question":"<p>In which of the following faculties the percent increase in the number of students was minimum from 2001 to 2002?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Arts","option2":"Science","option3":"Commerce","option4":"Medicine","option5":"Engineering","correct_option":"Medicine","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:34:20","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Percentage increase in the faculty of:<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Arts - &lt;sup&gt;4400-4200&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4200&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=4.761<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Commerce - &lt;sup&gt;9600-7700&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7700&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=24.675<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Science - &lt;sup&gt;8800-8400&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8400&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100= 4.76<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Engineering - &lt;sup&gt;7600-6300&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;6300&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=20.63<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Pharmacy - &lt;sup&gt;3600-2100&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2100&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=71.42<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Medicine - &lt;sup&gt;4000-3850&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3850&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=3.896<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Hence, the percentage increase in Medicine was minimum.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1958","question":"<p>What is a fiscal deficit?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"It is a gap between the value of the Exports and Import","option2":"It is a gap between Exports and Imports minus external borrowing ","option3":"It is a gap between total expenditure and total receipts of the Government ","option4":"It is the gap between total receipt  minus External Borrowing ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"It is a gap between total expenditure and total receipts of the Government ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 11:06:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1936","question":"<p>4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 6&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 12&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 30&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 75&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 315&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1260&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"315","option2":"75","option3":"12","option4":"6","option5":"30","correct_option":"75","qa_date":"2015-07-24 01:04:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>4&times;1.5&nbsp;= 6<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>6&times;2&nbsp;= 12<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>12&times;2.5&nbsp;= 30<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>30&times;3&nbsp;= <strong>90<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>90<\/strong>&times;3.5&nbsp;= 315<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>315&times;4= 1260<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>75 is replaced by <strong>90<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"2000","question":"<p>The hardware device that acts as both a switching and connecting unit is called a(n)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs-232 C Port    ","option2":"Concentrator ","option3":"Multiplexer ","option4":"Communication processor   ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Multiplexer ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:16:30","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1938","question":"<p>4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 9&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 29&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 111&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 556&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3325<\/p>\r\n","option1":"5","option2":"9","option3":"29","option4":"111","option5":"556","correct_option":"29","qa_date":"2015-07-24 01:13:39","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>4&times;1+1&nbsp;= 5<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>5&times;2-1&nbsp;= 9<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>9&times;3+1&nbsp;= <strong>28<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>28<\/strong>&times;4-1= 111<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>111&times;5+1= 556<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>29 is the wrong number.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>it is replaced by 28.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1897","question":"<p>What is the average profit earned (in crore Rs) for the given years?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"95","option2":"160","option3":"70","option4":"19","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"95","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:10:44","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Profits earned in year.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1997-98=Rs.(150-50)crores=Rs.100crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1998-99=Rs. (200-125) crores=Rs. 75crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1999-2000=Rs. (325-250) crores = Rs. 75crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2000-2001=Rs. (350-250) crores = Rs. 100crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2001-2002=Rs. (250-125) crores = Rs. 125crores<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, Required average<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. = &lt;sup&gt; (100+75+75+100+125) &lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. = &lt;sup&gt;475&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;\/sub&gt;= Rs.95crores<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1924","question":"<p>How many girls speak in Hindi?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"55","option2":"117","option3":"96","option4":"78","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"78","qa_date":"2015-07-23 04:48:46","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of girls who speak only Hindi =78<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1998","question":"<p>.&nbsp; The &ldquo;National Working Plan Code&rdquo; is a tool for management of ___?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Mining ","option2":"Defence structure          ","option3":"Contiguous diseases            ","option4":"Forest Resources","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Forest Resources","qa_date":"2015-07-25 18:58:51","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1912","question":"<p>What is the ratio between the number of students studying pharmacy in the years 2001 and 2002 respectively?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"4:3","option2":"3:2 ","option3":"2:3","option4":"7:12 ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"7:12 ","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:31:16","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of students studying pharmacy in 2001 = 2100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Number of students studying Pharmacy in 2002 = 3600<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required ratio = 2100: 3600 = 7:12<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1896","question":"<p>Which years is the percent profit earned the highest?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"2000-2001","option2":"1997-1998","option3":"1999-2000","option4":"2001-2002 ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"1997-1998","qa_date":"2015-07-21 23:05:47","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>percent profit for year, 2001-2002 = 100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1999-2000=30<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2000-2001=40<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Now, percent profit in year<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>1997-98= &lt;sup&gt;150-50&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>In 1998-99= &lt;sup&gt;200-125&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;125&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=60<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Obviously, it was the highest in 1997-98.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1999","question":"<p>Market information means<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Knowledge of shops and bazaars","option2":"Knowledge of shopping malls","option3":"Knowledge of customer profile and product mix","option4":"knowledge of various languages","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Knowledge of customer profile and product mix","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:12:50","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1899","question":"<p>For which course is the number of boys the minimum?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"E ","option2":"F","option3":"C","option4":"A","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"A","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:44:08","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Number of boys in course A is minimum i.e. zero.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"2003","question":"<p>Which out of the following is not DBMS software?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"DataBase ","option2":"FOXPRO","option3":"ORACLE","option4":"Sy BASE   ","option5":"Data base 2000 ","correct_option":"Data base 2000 ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:23:54","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1930","question":"<p><strong>I<\/strong>. 4x<sup>2 <\/sup>&ndash; 4x &ndash; 3 = 0&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>II<\/strong>.4y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>+ 12y + 5 = 0<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"5","qa_date":"2015-07-23 23:16:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>4x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 4x &ndash; 3 = 0 &nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>4x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 6x + 2x &ndash; 3 = 0&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2x(2x+1) + 3(2x+1) = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = - 3\/2; x = - 1\/2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>4y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>+ 12y + 5 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>4y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>+ 2y + 10y + 5 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2y(2y+1) + 5(2y+1) = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>y = - 5\/2; y = -1\/2<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1973","question":"<p>The RBI has power to print currency notes of up to Rs ____?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs.1000      ","option2":"Rs.5000","option3":"Rs.10,000   ","option4":"Rs.15,000","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Rs.1000      ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:50:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1944","question":"<p><span style=\"color:black; font-family:verdana,sans-serif; font-size:9pt\">In a group of 6 boys and 4 girls, four children are to be selected. In how many different ways can they be selected such that at least one boy should be there?<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"159","option2":"194","option3":"205 ","option4":"209","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"209","qa_date":"2015-07-23 21:53:51","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required number&nbsp; of ways&nbsp; = (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub>) + (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>) + (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>) + (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>4<\/sub>)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;= (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>) + (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>) + (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;x&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>C<sub>1<\/sub>) + (<sup>6<\/sup>C<sub>2<\/sub>)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;= (6 x 4) +(&lt;sup&gt;6 x 5&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;x&lt;sup&gt;4 x 3&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;) + &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;= (&lt;sup&gt;6 x 5 x 4&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3 x 2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;x4) + (&lt;sup&gt;6 x 5&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2x 1&lt;\/sub&gt;)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;= (24 + 90 + 80 + 15)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;= 209.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1982","question":"<p>Ms. Bachendri pal had undertaken a unique expedition for focusing attention on which of the following themes?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"National Integration   ","option2":"The Girl Child   ","option3":"Spirit of Adventure  ","option4":"One Nation One Family ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Spirit of Adventure  ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 15:36:07","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1932","question":"<p><strong>I<\/strong>. x<sup>2 <\/sup>+ 9x + 14 = 0&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>II.<\/strong>y<sup>2 <\/sup>+ y &ndash; 2 = 0<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"2","qa_date":"2015-07-23 23:31:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>+ 9x + 14 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = -2;-7<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>+ y &ndash; 2 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>y= 1; y = -2.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1914","question":"<p>In the year 2001, the number of students studying Arts and commerce together is what percent of the number of students studying these subjects other in 2002?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"76","option2":"85","option3":"83","option4":"79","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"85","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:33:25","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Total number of students in Arts and Commerce faculties in 2001=4200+7700=11900<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Total number of students in Arts and Commerce faculties in 2002 = 4400+9600 = 1400<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, required percentage = &lt;sup&gt;11900&lt;\/sup&gt;&frasl;&lt;sub&gt;14000&lt;\/sub&gt;&times;100=85<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"2005","question":"<p>In order to save a world document as a web page you need to&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Put the appropriate graphics and links on the document ","option2":"Save the document in simple text format ","option3":"Use your web browser as an editor and save as URL","option4":"Save as HTML  ","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"Save as HTML  ","qa_date":"2015-07-25 20:51:59","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"1907","question":"<p>How many students were there in the school during the year 1996?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1495","option2":"1600","option3":"1550","option4":"1700","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"1700","qa_date":"2015-07-24 00:39:07","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Total no of students who joined still 1996<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 300+250+500+450=1500<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Total no of students who left till 1996<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 250+350+400+300=1300<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; Net increase in the strength of the school<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 1500-1300=200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Initial strength of the school in 1992 = 1500<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, strength of the school during 1996= 1500+200=1700<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1931","question":"<p><strong>I<\/strong>. 4x<sup>2 <\/sup>= 49&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;II<\/strong>.9y<sup>2 <\/sup>&ndash; 66y + 121 = 0<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2015-07-23 23:26:32","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>4x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>= 49&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = +7\/2; - 7\/2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>9y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 66y + 121 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>9y<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>&ndash; 33y - 33y + 121 = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>3y(3y-11) - 11(3y-11) = 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>y = 11\/3<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"1974","question":"<p>Which of the following a type of banking application which authorises a bank to block a specific sum of money in an individual&rsquo;s bank account to be invested in an Initial Public Officer (IPO)?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"RTGS","option2":"ASBA","option3":"Prefunded Cheques   ","option4":"SCSBs ","option5":"None of these  ","correct_option":"ASBA","qa_date":"2015-07-25 16:52:27","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""}]